hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft now
not a lot has happened on the build off
front maybe they're scared or maybe i've
just won maybe this is as far as it goes
but mumbo and iskall haven't really
changed anything since the last episode
and i don't blame them because it takes
an awful lot of time to do something
like that but i think since they're not
doing anything maybe we could add a
little bit more but first there's a few
things to tick off the list first of all
what on earth is going on here i spotted
this guy earlier then he seems to be
having a bit of a mud bath i don't know
how he got in here but he's actually
able to walk around i think i saw him
over here first
are you okay
what is doc doing in that house over
there there's some sort of shenanigans
going on i know it over here we have
been repopulating the village there are
villagers galore once more and there are
bread for all of them so basically in
order to keep this village alive we
simply have to just keep repopulating it
with lots of villagers but i've done
that so many times now that it's getting
a little bit old so i'm just gonna do
that in the background to keep this
place alive that that's the salmon man
or the salman he's still in here
this this guy's still in here still
doing his thing although he's no longer
spinning i think at some point we'll
have to let him out but one of the
biggest additions to the hermitville
village
is not this not that it's that
there's a giant spaceship
well i assume it's a spaceship or a
space station or something so we
definitely need to go and check this out
for sure like what on earth it's not in
the boundaries of hermitville itself
what
oh
again
thankfully i keep elytra on me but i
need to get that repaired
so look at this what a magnificent
looking build so let's take a look at
the end here what have we got a sign
welcome to ufo outfitters shop
and then there's a convex side well
that's the sign of cuban scar let's head
up on
oh
it totally looks like i'm being abducted
oh that's clever i like that it's like a
tractor beam how did i how did i not see
that you have been abducted by concorp
ufo yes of course i have yeah so this is
a concorp venture
what are they selling that's what i want
to know
stone cutters for one diamond why on
earth would i need 16 stone cutters so
they're selling
all sorts smooth quartz wow
that is that's a good deal two diamonds
for that much quartz so they seem to be
selling a variety of things in here why
you would need 16 smithing tables
but this is a handy shop to have
nonetheless especially with this quartz
i feel like sahara could even just buy
all of this out
and say yeah we're gonna stop quartz and
sell it for maybe a little bit more the
question is
how do i get out
i genuinely don't see a way out i think
i've been bamboozled here i think i'm a
little bit stuck there must there must
be an exit
somewhere who makes a shop
and doesn't put an exit on oh wait
totally me remember when i made the
pickle shop
[Laughter]
i think i have to break my way out of
here because i can't see an exit
anywhere oh dear
the last thing i want to do is break
something but i don't know how to leave
all right
i've got a i've just got to go
so this is going to be tricky i'm just
going to i'm going to try and leave and
replace no no i failed i was going to
try and replace it as i fell so i'm just
gonna have to do a flyby
no okay now i'm back in all right there
we go no ah here we go where is it
this is much more difficult than i
thought concorp make an exit in your
spaceship
yes one okay we're back to square one
yes yes yes yes yes
i i am not kidding that took about 15
minutes just to get out of this
spaceship
i think i've been pranked and it wasn't
even meant to be a prank um concord
please please make an exit somehow i
think you forgot the door
right well now that that's out of the
way we can inspect some of the other
things that have been going on in the
village one of which is a pillager
outpost and it says attention patrols
this is a legit outpost keep patrolling
and i
assume that this is
something to do with cub yep there we go
there's cub and there's cubs assistant
so they're clearly up to no good i don't
really know what the outpost does
maybe it's to encourage the pillagers i
don't know now i've been thinking about
how we can interrupt mumbo's rocket
and i've come up with an idea so we
don't actually need to put anything
right in front of it okay we don't need
to put something directly in front of
here we could make a crane attached to
the building here and the crane doesn't
actually need to touch this at all all
it needs to do
is touch this bit so this is as far as
it goes mumbo will likely assume that
i've missed altogether and still launch
the rocket and then it's going to get
caught when it gets past and it should
stop his rocket from reaching the build
limit so i was thinking that it could go
around this area
and then have a bit of an overhang and
then hang some sort of crate here just
so it's in the way
so
let's build this really really quickly
so i decided to make this crane thing
and i actually went for a design that i
kind of made in a different video using
the scaffolding as the main part but it
just looks so luminescent that i decided
to get rid of it i tried oak wood and
then i just reverted back to spruce to
try and make it fit in with everything
else so experiment failed however made a
very quick crane
there we have it so i've obviously not
made this any taller because i don't
need to but i needed to stop mumbo but
i've been rather clever about how i've
done it so
i've got my crane and it is sticking
over the edge of this like it is still
supported i made sure it looks like it's
a bit complicated under there however
it is still it still feels like it's
part of the build it doesn't feel
completely out of place it's got the
counterweight there and then it's got
some like
barrels as crates
now here's the thing i didn't want to
put it straight over the top of
the rocket here because that would have
been too obvious so what i'm hoping is
that mumbo doesn't really notice and he
goes ha ha ha ha this is still going to
work green missed it and then he's going
to launch it anyway and what's going to
happen is that because this is
overhanging it's going to get caught on
that and then stop
halfway up
in its launch so essentially it will go
up about
that much
so it would end up going
oh
i don't think it would go higher than my
house but that that's quite a big
leap up from where it is maybe what i'll
do is actually move this back again and
have it hanging there that looks way
less suspicious
than where it is right now in fact i'm
gonna do that see if that makes a big
difference
so let's check at the moment the sign is
actually going to be interrupted by that
block so
i can actually move this
okay there we are we are now finished
and that looks like it should just pass
straight over it
i have no idea if mumbo's gonna fall for
it
but that looks pretty convincing that
i've missed it all together
and actually we might need to remove
that because if if that doesn't stop it
that certainly will i need to start
thinking about defense and longevity i
need to stop mumbo getting higher on his
house i need to stop iscal and i need to
stop whatever's going on over here looks
like concord really are looking to do
something with this build-off and i
think as far as the build goes it's done
nothing but add to this build you can
kind of this actually looks like it's
just coming out of the side of this part
of the build
and i think a crane on this kind of
thing looks really at home you only
really learn or find out what this is by
flying around it and taking a look and
then you find out it's actually a crane
on a platform which it doesn't look
nearly as supported as it perhaps should
do but i can definitely fix that now
that the defense is done let's head back
to the old lands because i've got a
couple of elytra that need repairing
basically
sahara
is now finished if we go into the
storage room you will see that we have
collected
over 600 shulker boxes from a giant end
raiding or end busting session we've got
all of the shulker boxes we could ever
need for the system our trusted sahara
technicians will then load up all these
shulker boxes into
whatever this stuff does
and then
we will be ready for the grand opening
now that's more my style what will we do
for this grand opening you say well i
don't want to give it too much away
however
there's a little bit of tidying up that
needs to be done in preparation
but i think we can safely say that in
the next episode sahara will officially
open and the issue that
well maybe i don't need to say the issue
because you can see it right in front of
you there's just
torch spam
there's
no
tidiness here
whatsoever so what i'm going to do is
spend a little bit of time
creating something that's more worthy of
an opening so when people are in here it
looks a little bit more finished than
just torch spam which is gonna mean
hiding some stuff under carpet
making a stage
all sorts of things
the obvious thing for me would be
simply to add a huge carpet with loads
of glowstone underneath but i don't know
about that i could do consecutive rings
i'm gonna have to think about this a
little bit
i don't actually have any glowstone so
i'm gonna go and have to borrow some
from uh old buddy old pal mumbo
jumbo leo
i just need to remember
how to get there
most people run through this i just fly
this looks different
this looks very different
huh
what do these do
oh
this is amazing
he hasn't labeled them though
it breaks them all or some of them
that's confusing oh
wow
now this is fun
it's taking a while to load
but there's loads of bamboo
so what does this do
does this collect i probably shouldn't
be messing
with the very complicated machinery
oh this is absolutely insane
look at this
mumbo what have you been doing
you should be building sahara
i've now got to press all the buttons
uh-oh i sent another one off
oh my goodness
it runs along
and it punches out the pumpkins
that is so cool i don't even know what's
going on there it's like a pumpkin
printing machine this is like a this is
like a theme park press all the buttons
magical stuff happens there's a farm
and i think well what i came for was
some glowstone from here ah there we go
oh my goodness
there's
so many
materials in here
so this is the benefit of knowing a lot
of redstone now before i leave i'm going
to make sure that these machines make
their way home again so that i don't
break them by leaving
it doesn't look like
it's being collected oh no there they go
the collection system's off and
there we go
no it's not sending it off again is it
what is this look at this machine it's
it's like a car
oh well this is this is like willy
wonka's chocolate factory seriously look
at all the magical things that are
happening i'm like five minutes in and
it's still going i'm hoping it ends soon
because i want to leave ah there we go
looks like this should be the end of it
finally
okay
we could leave now
i hope i didn't break anything
thanks mumbo as always
well that was a much more exciting
adventure for glowstone than i was
prepared for but now
i can fill in this area with a bit
better lighting
than i have been so i've made a bit of
an a in here and then all i need to put
in is a sea lantern in the middle and
you've got the architect logo obviously
it's a two block center because of that
chest but there's not a lot i can do
about that but this lights it up really
really nicely without any
fuss whatsoever
now to cover it up with a carpet you may
be wondering why i left a space here
well i thought this could be our little
stage or temporary stage for the actual
opening
there we go
we've got a brand new temporary wooden
stage although i don't know whether this
will ever get removed so this is where
the podium is going to be like when we
have our big grand opening we're going
to obviously cut the ribbon we're going
to have everybody stand here and this
will be where the presentation takes
place now for our special guests that
we're going to maybe have i want to
create like a little stage up there or
for the ceo of the company and that may
or may not be me
we'll find out and hopefully this grand
opening will go really well so you can
see i've made the architect logo there
i've lit this up with a bit better than
the torch spam
and hopefully next episode this will be
ready to go i've spent a little bit of
time and i think i'm pretty much there
with everything that we're going to need
for the big grand opening
this weekend so if we go up here i have
added just a little bit i've removed all
of the torch span that was here i've
added a few trees i need to figure out
how to fill this space here but i'm sure
it won't be too difficult maybe a carpet
or something very very simple
nothing too major however it does look
slightly more finished and complete
than it did at the start with just
torches everywhere and i think a lot of
you will be very happy to see how clean
this has become i've also decorated
around this giving this a trim so when
you see the minecart come along with
your goodies
then it will go through here and anyone
that's sitting down and having a little
meal can see it then drop through there
and into the system now i did actually
have a little word with iscow about
where we're at and we decided what we're
going to stock we decided the prices on
things and he's going to make sure that
everything is working
over here
in the warehouse so with that done
and with the conversation that we've had
that leaves sahara very much open
to open so to speak so it's time to get
my like outfit on and in the next
episode i guarantee you
sahara
will be opening
and we will be generating
at least
a couple of diamonds
i also am going to reduce the price
of my electric course because people are
having such a hard time with it what i'm
going to do
is change it
to
two runs
for one diamond so you get double the
runs for your money
that means people can get a bit more
addicted to it because i'm hoping that
they will produce a few more results for
me because i've been doing this electric
course just like when i'm a bit bored i
just sort of go around it and i've
actually managed to do
a no hit run twice but unfortunately i
have no evidence for that because i
wasn't recording however
it is possible i have done it
not that time but it is possible and i
reckon that if i was recording those
exact runs i probably would have beaten
my score
we need to come up with a better system
of travel between
the 114 village
and the main island because seriously it
takes so long
to get between them and the path is so
weird because no one's changed it since
day one we just need to a bit of a
better system
now that i'm actually back in the
village i discovered something very very
upsetting there was me spending a lot of
time
detailing this whole thing and i
actually forgot to include the time
lapse so there's the time lapse of me
detailing this build obviously it's not
mega exciting but you can see me going
around putting all the windows in etc
it's just a formality basically there's
no way that the inside of this build can
be used it's so
unpredictable
but
what i learnt
very recently is that my house actually
isn't the tallest
if you remember last episode i made sure
that we were just two blocks taller than
scars house so this is 63.5
look what scar's done over in the
distance
he has added
two end rods and an iron bar
he added like a little satellite dish
and i'm pretty sure if i'm not very much
mistaken
that
makes his house
top of the list
at
165 blocks tall
now if that isn't cheeky
i don't know what is but two can
definitely play at that game scar
you may have been top temporarily but
that is ridiculous so
mine is 63.5
64.
65 66 67 we are 167 that is 165
we are back on top two can play at that
game good times with scar don't you
worry about that
and that doesn't look out of place at
all
this
can't end well
i'm not gonna lie i don't think that
this
family feud is going to end particularly
well i really hope that mumbo and iskall
get on and see what's going on because i
really want this to continue i mean i
don't really know where build height is
it's like 200 and something or other so
it's like maybe about here
not sure
but there's still a huge amount for us
to build before we reach the top and i
for one can't wait to see what happens
i predict
that by the end of this little feud
we're going to have
the most ridiculous thing
that has ever happened on hermitcraft
end up somewhere around here
and
honestly
i'm just a bit excited so i'm afraid
that's all from me everybody i'm afraid
today we did quite a lot of preparation
stuff getting sahara ready and trying to
make sure that our house still remains
on top
however sometimes it just ends up that
way and we just have to we have to do
quite a lot of preparation to get
anywhere so with the sun setting i will
say thank you very much for watching and
good bye